Guide to the Edmond Pauker Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Business Files, 1898-1960; Series II; 14.6; (36 boxes)
  - CLIENT FILES
    - Spina, Harold, Walter Hannan, and Edward Heyman
      - Stovepipe Hat
        - Contracts, 1942-44, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 961)
        - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 39, Folder 962)
    - Stanley, Harry
      - Beautiful Baby (formerly entitled A Man and a Horse )
        - Contract, 1956 Feb 2 (Box 39, Folder 963)
        - Correspondence, 1955-56, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 964)
    - Stein, Leo Walther
      - Die Sommerkönigin: contract, 1928 Jul 1 (Box 39, Folder 965)
    - Stein, Sol
      - The Illegitimist (formerly entitled Napoleon ): correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 39, Folder 966-969)
        Incl: Charles Boyer, Claude Rains
    - Sterk, Wilhelm
      - Alle Wege führen zur Liebe: contracts, 1932 (Box 39, Folder 970)
    - Stern, Henry R. and Joseph W. Stern
      - Contract: general, 1923 Sep 5 (Box 39, Folder 971)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden
      - Rebound: contracts, 1931 (Box 39, Folder 972)
    - Straus, Oscar
      - Contracts: general, 1928-41 (Box 39, Folder 973-974)
      - Correspondence: general, 1954-55 (Box 39, Folder 975)
      - Statements: general, 1931 (Box 39, Folder 976)
    - Szántó, Armand and Michael Szécésén
      - The Romantic Woman ( Die romantische Frau ): contract, 1937 May 11 (Box 39, Folder 977)
      - Tempo 120 ( Százhuszas tempó ): contracts, 1930-35 (Box 39, Folder 978)
    - Székely, Hans
      - Contract: general, 1936 Apr 29 (Box 40, Folder 979)
      - It Was In Port Said: contract, 1941 Nov 26 (Box 40, Folder 980)
      - The Portrait of Miss M. C.: contracts, 1940-43 (Box 40, Folder 981)
      - Tragedy In Minor Key (novel): contract, 1940 Jan 8 (Box 40, Folder 982)
    - Székely, Hans and Emjo Basshe
      - Bread: contract, 1939 Jun 15 (Box 40, Folder 983)
    - Székely, Hans and Zoltán Egyed
      - Dramatic School ( Színiiskola ): contracts, 1937-38 (Box 40, Folder 984)
        Incl: contracts for adaptations by Adelyn Bushnell and Jacques Deval
    - Székely, Hans and Szöke Szakáll
      - Der Mann dem nicht Zu helfen ist: contracts, 1939 Feb 23 (Box 40, Folder 985)
        Incl: contract for adaptation by Benjamin F. Glazer
    - Szenes, Béla
      - May Moon ( Az olasz asszony ): contracts, 1930 (Box 40, Folder 986)
        Incl: contracts for adaptation by M. L. Fielding
      - The Rascal: contract, 1936 May 22 (Box 40, Folder 987)
    - Szép, Ernö
      - Patika: contracts, 1934 (Box 40, Folder 988)
        Incl: contract for adaptation by Alexander Kenedi
    - Szerb, Antal
      - Pendragon legenda (novel): contract, 1938 Aug 22 (Box 40, Folder 989)
        For translation by Nicholas Leslie
    - Szomory, Dezsö
      - Alice Takats ( The Light Behind the Shadow ): contract, 1934 Jun 26 (Box 40, Folder 990)
        Adapted by Jose Ruben
    - Tamás, István
      - Contracts: general, 1942-43 (Box 40, Folder 991)
      - Moscow-Paris and Return ( Moskau-Paris und Retour ) (novel): contract, 1942 Mar 12 (Box 40, Folder 992)
        See also: Menyhért Lengyel: Silk Stockings, Box 29, folder 683
      - A moszkvai lány: contract, 1942 Jul 31 (Box 40, Folder 993)
      - Sergeant Nikola (book): contracts, 1942-43 (Box 40, Folder 994)
      - The Students of Spalato (novel): contracts, 1943 Feb 12 (Box 40, Folder 995)
    - Thomas, Dorothy
      - The Wrong Woman: statements, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 996)
    - Toldy, János
      - Swoboda kontra Hitler (novel): contract, 1939 Sep 18 (Box 40, Folder 997)
    - Török, Rezsö
      - Magdaléna: contract, 1940 Sep 12 (Box 40, Folder 998)
    - Török, Rezsö and Tamás Emöd
      - Two Girls on the Street ( Két lány az utcán ): contracts, 1930 (Box 40, Folder 999)
    - Tors, Iván and Andor DeSoos
      - Come and Get Me ( Keep Your Distance ): contracts, 1942 (Box 40, Folder 1000)
    - Treadwell, Sophie
      - Machinal: contract, 1935 Aug 22 (Box 40, Folder 1001)
    - Tretiakow, S.
      - Roar China ( Brülle China ): contract, 1930 Mar 1 (Box 40, Folder 1002)
        Adapted by Leo Lania
    - Turney, Catherine and Jerry Horwin
      - My Dear Children
        - Contracts, 1938-50 (Box 40, Folder 1003)
          Incl: contracts with Otto Preminger
        - Correspondence, 1952-55 (Box 40, Folder 1004-1005)
        - Statement, 1953 Feb 2 (Box 40, Folder 1006)
    - Underwood, Sophie Kerr and Anna Steene Richardson
      - Big Hearted Herbert: contracts, 1934-35 (Box 40, Folder 1007)
    - Ungar, Hermann
      - The Red General ( Der rote General ): contracts, 1928-30 (Box 40, Folder 1008)
    - Unruh, Fritz von
      - Phaea: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 40, Folder 1009)
    - Vadnai, László
      - Tisztelt Ház!: contract, 1935 Sep 30 (Box 40, Folder 1010)
        For adaptation by Andor de Soos
    - Vas, Stephen
      - Uncle Mary (story): contract, 1949 Dec 9 (Box 40, Folder 1011)
        Contract with P. G. Wodehouse for adaptation of the story for publication
    - Vaszary, János
      - Jo házbol valo úrilány: contracts, 1932 Aug 25 (Box 40, Folder 1012)
      - Ladies and Gentlemen ( Hölgyek és Urak ): contracts, 1937-38 (Box 40, Folder 1013)
        Incl: contract for adaptation by Rosalind Ivan
      - Red Beast ( Vörös bestia ): contracts, 1934 (Box 40, Folder 1014)
    - Vecsey, Armand
      - Hang 'Em All: contract, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1015)
        For adaptation by Alice Mattullath
    - Vein, Norman
      - Melody: contracts, 1954-55 (Box 40, Folder 1016)
    - Victor, Victor
      - Soliloquy: contracts, 1938 (Box 40, Folder 1017)
      - Star of Navarre: contract, 1937 Oct 28 (Box 41, Folder 1018)
    - Von Hutten, Baroness
      - Lives of a Woman (novel): contracts, 1936 May 1 (Box 41, Folder 1019)
    - Vulpius, Paul
      - Help Yourself
        - Contracts, 1936-39, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1020-1021)
        - Statements, 1948-54 (Box 41, Folder 1022)
      - Up She Goes ( Ho-Ruck ): contract, 1934 Jun 26 (Box 41, Folder 1023)
    - Walden, William
      - Metropole: contracts, 1949 (Box 41, Folder 1024)
    - Walker, James J.
      - Untitled autobiography: contracts, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 1025)
        Written with Géza Herczeg
    - Watters, George Manker and Arthur Hopkins
      - Burlesque
        - Contracts, 1933 Dec (Box 41, Folder 1026)
        - Statement, 1933 Dec 22 (Box 41, Folder 1027)
    - Wayne, Bernie
      - Contracts: general, 1952-57 (Box 41, Folder 1028)
      - Correspondence: general, 1956-57 (Box 41, Folder 1029)
    - Weitzenkorn, Louis
      - Burglar Strike: contracts, 1937 (Box 41, Folder 1030)
    - Wells, Burton
      - Mr. Preedy Plots: contract, 1939 Aug 29 (Box 41, Folder 1031)
    - Wendt, Stephen and Clarence Brooks
      - Trojan Horse: contract, 1940 Jul 8 (Box 41, Folder 1032)
    - Wilde, Cornel
      - One Fair Day: contract, 1939 Jan 22 (Box 41, Folder 1033)
    - Willner, Eugene and Heinz Reichert
      - Blossom Time ( Drei Maderlhaus )
        Adapted by Dorothy Donnelly
        - Contracts, 1912-27 (Box 41, Folder 1034)
        - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 41, Folder 1035)
        - Correspondence, 1953-57 (Box 41, Folder 1036-1037)
    - Winsloe, Christa
      - Mädchen in Uniform ( Gestern und Heute ): contracts, 1932-36 (Box 41, Folder 1038)
    - Wolf, Edmund and Ludwig Hirschfeld
      - Not For Children ( Das ist nichts für Kinder ): contracts, 1939-41 (Box 41, Folder 1039)
        Incl: contract for adaptation by Wesley Towner
    - Yost, Tibor and Eugen Scharin
      - Lola: contracts, 1934-35 (Box 42, Folder 1040)
    - Zilahy, Lajos
      - Correspondence: general, 1951-58 (Box 42, Folder 1041-1042)
      - The Angry Angel [book?]: statements, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 1043)
      - The Dukays (book): statements, 1950-57 (Box 42, Folder 1044)
    - Zsolt, Béla
      - Oktogon: contracts, 1933-34 (Box 42, Folder 1045)
    - Zweig, Stefan
      - Volpone: contracts, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1046)
        Based upon the original by Ben Jonson
    - Unidentified authors
      - Are You a Mason? ( Die Logenbruder ): contracts, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 1047)
      - Blume von Hawaii: contract, 1939 Aug 17 (Box 42, Folder 1048)
      - Das Dreimaederlhaus: contract, 1942 Oct 30 (Box 42, Folder 1049)
      - Fuszer es Csemege: contract, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1050)
      - Der lächerliche Sir Anthony: contract, 1935 Jul 31 (Box 42, Folder 1051)
      - Nights In Cairo: contracts, 1930-31 (Box 42, Folder 1052)
      - "Reise nach Faremido" and "Die Legende von der tausendgesichtigen Seele" (stories): contract, 1937 May 24 (Box 42, Folder 1053)
  - GENERAL FILES
    The General Files subseries (Boxes 43-50) consists of four sections: Contracts, Correspondence, Financial Papers, and Other Business Papers, all of which are arranged alphabetically by name, subject, or type of material. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name and then chronologically.
    - Contracts
      - Athenaeum, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1054)
      - Contract logbook, 1926-39 (Box 43, Folder 1055-1056)
        With note from Elisabeth Marton, 1960 Oct 30
      - Contract templates, 1932-45, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1057)
      - Dr. Alexander Marton, 1923-38 (Box 43, Folder 1058)
      - Endrey, Eugene and Paul Yartin, 1932-39 (Box 43, Folder 1059-1060)
      - Field Moses & Jones Inc., 1937 May 4 (Box 43, Folder 1061)
      - George Marton Verlag, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 1062)
      - International Copyright Bureau, 1925-27, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1063)
      - Laura D. Wilck, 1933, 1935 (Box 43, Folder 1064)
      - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures Corp., 1935 (Box 43, Folder 1065)
      - Playmarket, Inc., 1940 (Box 43, Folder 1066)
    - Correspondence
      - "A" general, 1935, 1953-56 (Box 43, Folder 1067)
      - Aczél, Benö, 1953-56 (Box 43, Folder 1068)
      - Amade, Stephany, 1948 (Box 43, Folder 1069)
      - American Broadcasting Company, 1954-55 (Box 43, Folder 1070)
      - Anderson, Raymond W., 1952-53 (Box 44, Folder 1071)
      - "B" general, 1953-57 (Box 44, Folder 1072-1073)
      - Barnett, Paul, 1954-55 (Box 44, Folder 1074)
        Incl: two photographs
      - Bass & Harlow, 1954 (Box 44, Folder 1075)
      - Bayfield, St. Clair, 1953-55 (Box 44, Folder 1076)
      - Bell, Doris, 1953 (Box 44, Folder 1077)
      - Bengis, Jerome, 1953-54 (Box 44, Folder 1078)
      - Blaükopf, Leona, 1955 (Box 44, Folder 1079)
      - Blum, Gustav, 1952-57 (Box 44, Folder 1080)
      - Burns, Anne, 1952-55 (Box 44, Folder 1081)
      - "C" general, 1952-59 (Box 44, Folder 1082-1083)
      - CBS Television, 1953-55 (Box 44, Folder 1084)
      - Clement, Victor, 1953-58 (Box 44, Folder 1085)
      - Cobey, Herbert T., 1951-54 (Box 44, Folder 1086-1088)
      - Colton, Edward, 1950-55 (Box 44, Folder 1089)
      - Conrad, Earl, 1954-55 (Box 44, Folder 1090)
      - "D" general, 1953-56 (Box 44, Folder 1091)
      - DeBrosse, Thomas
        See: Max Fenyö, Box 44, folder 1103
      - Deming, Benton Hawthorne, 1953-56 (Box 44, Folder 1092)
      - DeWitt, Francis, 1952-56 (Box 44, Folder 1093)
      - Dr. Jan Van Loewen, Ltd., 1956 (Box 44, Folder 1094)
      - "E" general, 1953-56 (Box 44, Folder 1095)
      - Ebenstein, Morris, 1954-56 (Box 44, Folder 1096-1097)
      - Eichel, Leslie, 1954-56 (Box 44, Folder 1098)
      - "F" general, 1933-56 (Box 44, Folder 1099)
      - Farrar, Straus & Young, Inc., 1954 (Box 44, Folder 1100)
      - Felix Bloch Erben, 1935, 1953-55 (Box 44, Folder 1101-1102)
      - Fenyö, Max, 1953-56 (Box 44, Folder 1103)
      - Fields, David N., 1959-60 (Box 44, Folder 1104)
      - Firner, Walter, 1954-56 (Box 44, Folder 1105)
      - Fryer, Robert, 1953-56 (Box 44, Folder 1106)
      - "G" general, 1923-56 (Box 45, Folder 1107)
      - Gilbert, Clement Scott
        See: Vajda-Gilbert Playwrights, Box 47, folder 1189
      - Gilbert Miller, 1951-54 (Box 45, Folder 1108)
      - Giusti, Arndt, 1955-56 (Box 45, Folder 1109)
      - Glickman, Will, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1109)
      - Golden, John, 1952-56 (Box 45, Folder 1110)
      - Goode, Peter L., 1955 (Box 45, Folder 1111)
      - Gordon, Paul, 1953-55 (Box 45, Folder 1111)
      - Gosztonyi, Adám, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 1111)
      - "H" general, 1952-57 (Box 45, Folder 1112)
      - Habernal, Erik, 1952-54 (Box 45, Folder 1113)
      - Hans Bartsch Plays, 1951-52 (Box 45, Folder 1114)
      - Hollander, Vera, 1953-54 (Box 45, Folder 1115)
      - "I" general, 1954-55 (Box 45, Folder 1116)
      - International Copyright Bureau, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 1117)
      - "J" general, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 1118)
      - J. Walter Thompson Company, 1953-57 (Box 45, Folder 1119)
      - Jay Lurye Associates, 1954-55 (Box 45, Folder 1120)
      - "K" general, 1953-54 (Box 45, Folder 1121)
      - Kaufman, Martin, 1953-54 (Box 45, Folder 1122)
      - Kingman-Speelman, Zaya, 1953-54 (Box 45, Folder 1123)
        Incl: Cecil B. DeMille (transcripts)
      - Korda, Beatrice Maria, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 1124)
      - Koretz, Paul, 1951-54 (Box 45, Folder 1125-1126)
      - "L" general, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 1127)
      - Ladies Home Journal, 1951-54 (Box 45, Folder 1128)
      - Laura D. Wilck Literary Agency, 1950-54 (Box 45, Folder 1129-1130)
      - "M" general, 1951-60 (Box 45, Folder 1131)
      - Mendelssohn, Evelyn, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 1132)
      - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, 1951-59 (Box 45, Folder 1133)
      - "N" general, 1953-58 (Box 45, Folder 1134)
      - Nagy, Margit, 1957-58 (Box 45, Folder 1135)
        See also: Refugee writers, Box 45, folder 1152
      - Nagy, Vince, 1951-58 (Box 45, Folder 1136)
      - National Broadcasting Company, Inc., 1955 (Box 45, Folder 1137)
      - "O" general, 1953, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 1138)
      - "P" general, 1953-59 (Box 45, Folder 1139-1140)
      - Paramount Pictures Corporation, 1952-56 (Box 45, Folder 1141-1143)
      - Parella, Anthony, 1955-56 (Box 45, Folder 1144)
      - Paul Kohner, Inc., 1951-54 (Box 45, Folder 1145-1147)
      - Pauli, Hertha, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1148)
      - Payer, John J., 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1148)
      - Preminger, Otto, 1953-56 (Box 45, Folder 1149)
      - "R" general, 1951-59 (Box 45, Folder 1150-1151)
      - Refugee writers, 1956-58 (Box 45, Folder 1152)
        Incl: Ernö Horváth, Edith Kós, Margit Nagy, Alice Reisz, András Székely, Joseph Szücs
      - Reinhardt, Wolfgang, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 1153)
      - Ricono, Connie, 1952-54 (Box 45, Folder 1154-1155)
      - Robinson, David, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 1156)
      - Rolfs, Hans W., 1953-57 (Box 46, Folder 1156)
      - "S" general, 1953-59 (Box 46, Folder 1157-1158)
      - Sachs, Mary Koues, 1955-58 (Box 46, Folder 1159)
      - Samuel French, Inc., 1953-58 (Box 46, Folder 1160)
      - Schaffner, John, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1161)
      - Schnitzler, Henry, 1955-56 (Box 46, Folder 1161)
      - Sekely, Steve, 1954-58 (Box 46, Folder 1162-1164)
      - Selwin-Tait, Monica, 1953, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 1165)
      - Shelton, Paul E., 1952-54 (Box 46, Folder 1165)
      - Shinkman, Paul A., 1953-57 (Box 46, Folder 1165)
      - Shinsel, Ruth, 1954-57 (Box 46, Folder 1166)
      - Shubert, Milton I., 1951-54 (Box 46, Folder 1167)
      - Sieransky, Andrei, 1956-58 (Box 46, Folder 1168)
      - Simcoe, Ben, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1168)
      - Society of Authors' Representatives, Inc., 1951-59 (Box 46, Folder 1169-1172)
      - Solomon, James and Shirley, 1957-58 (Box 46, Folder 1173)
      - Steele, Jack, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 1174)
      - Steelman, Norman, 1955-56 (Box 46, Folder 1174)
      - Stuart, William W., 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1174)
      - Sullivan, A. M., 1957 (Box 46, Folder 1175)
      - Swan, Paul, 1959 (Box 46, Folder 1175)
      - Sweedler, John J., 1950-54 (Box 46, Folder 1176)
      - Szenes, Piroska, 1958-59, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1177)
      - "T" general, 1955-62 (Box 46, Folder 1178-1179)
      - Tallant, Robert, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 1180)
      - Tamás, István, 1952-55 (Box 46, Folder 1181)
      - Theatre By-the-Sea, 1954-55 (Box 46, Folder 1182)
      - Theatre Guild, 1951-59 (Box 46, Folder 1183)
      - Thornbury, Ethel M., 1957-58 (Box 46, Folder 1184)
      - Thompson, Olean, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1184)
      - Tippett, Irene C., 1955 (Box 46, Folder 1184)
      - Twentieth Century Fox, 1951-55 (Box 46, Folder 1185)
      - "U" general, 1952-57 (Box 46, Folder 1186)
      - Universal Pictures Company, Inc., 1952-59 (Box 46, Folder 1187)
      - "V" general, 1953-58 (Box 46, Folder 1188)
      - Vajda-Gilbert Playwrights, 1952-57 (Box 47, Folder 1189-1192)
      - Verlag Kurt Desch München, 1952-54 (Box 47, Folder 1193)
      - "W" general, 1952-58 (Box 47, Folder 1194)
      - Warner Bros. Pictures, Inc., 1953-54 (Box 47, Folder 1195)
      - Waxman, Arthur
        See: Jay Lurye Associates, Box 45, folder 1120
      - Werfel, Alma Mahler, 1952-54 (Box 47, Folder 1196)
      - Whitney, Walter R., 1952-53 (Box 47, Folder 1197)
        Incl: Harald Bromley
      - Whitney, Walter R., 1954 (Box 47, Folder 1198)
      - Whitney, Walter R., 1955-56 (Box 47, Folder 1199)
      - "Y" general, 1956, 1958 (Box 47, Folder 1200)
      - "Z" general, 1955-57 (Box 47, Folder 1201)
    - Financial Papers
      - Bond coupons and receipts, 1934, 1935 (Box 47, Folder 1202)
      - Cash book, 1954-58 (Box 47, Folder 1203)
      - Check registers, 1953-55 (Box 47, Folder 1204-1207)
      - Check registers, 1955-57 (Box 48, Folder 1208-1212)
      - General journal, 1954-58 (Box 48, Folder 1213)
      - General ledger, 1954-58 (Box 48, Folder 1214)
      - Loan note, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 1215)
      - Receipts: Business expenses, 1952-54 (Box 48, Folder 1216-1217)
      - Receipts: Business expenses, 1955-56 (Box 49, Folder 1218-1219)
      - Returned check, 1928 (Box 49, Folder 1220)
      - Statements: Samuel French, Inc., 1953-59 (Box 49, Folder 1221-1225)
      - Stock certificate: Production Development, Inc., 1957 Apr (Box 49, Folder 1226)
    - Other Business Papers
      - Certificate of incorporation of Edmond Pauker, Inc., 1940 Jun 21 (Box 49, Folder 1227)
      - Deposition, 1939 Sep (Box 49, Folder 1228)
      - Insurance policy and memorandum, 1934, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 1229)
      - List of publishers, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1230)
      - Notices to stockholders, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 1231)
      - Play reviews, 1951-55 (Box 49, Folder 1232-1236)
      - Play reviews, 1956-59 (Box 50, Folder 1237-1243)
      - Powers of attorney, 1923-35 (Box 50, Folder 1244)
      - Television and film reviews, 1957-59 (Box 50, Folder 1245-1246)
      - Television material, 1957-59 (Box 50, Folder 1247)
      - Theater programs, 1951-58 (Box 50, Folder 1248-1249)
- Personal Papers, 1926-64; Series III; 0.4; (1 box)
  Personal Papers (Box 51) are arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
  - Autograph album, 1926-64 (Box 51, Folder 1250)
  - Patent granted to Emmerich Partos for "improvements in or relating to travelling bags, trunks and the like", 1932 Sep 16 (Box 51, Folder 1251)
  - Receipts: Personal expenses, 1952-54 (Box 51, Folder 1252-1253)
  - Receipts: Personal expenses, 1955-57 (Box 51, Folder 1254-1256)
  - Tri-dimensional cinema screen invention: correspondence and contracts, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 1257)
- Oversize, 1925-60; 1.75; (1 box)
  Oversize material from the Client Files subseries of Series II is housed in Box 52.
  - Brown, Beth
    - Correspondence: general, 1954 Apr 20 (Box 52, Folder 1258)
  - Lengyel, Menyhért
    - Silk Stockings: reviews and publicity, 1955-57 (Box 52, Folder 1259)
  - Molnár, Ferenc
    - The Swan: contract, 1929 Dec 10 (Box 52, Folder 1260)
    - The Swan: copyright, 1925 Jul 11 (Box 52, Folder 1261)
  - Rieseberg, Harry E.
    - Correspondence: general, 1960 (Box 52, Folder 1262)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 2.15; (2 boxes)
  Boxes 53 and 54 contain fragile originals for which preservation photocopies have been made. Box 53 contains oversize material. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 2, folders 45-6 (Box 53, Folder 1263)
  - Box 3, folder 55 (Box 53, Folder 1264)
  - Box 7, folders 114-16 (Box 53, Folder 1265)
  - Box 9, folder 148 (Box 53, Folder 1266)
  - Box 12, folder 188 (Box 53, Folder 1267)
  - Box 12, folder 205 (Box 53, Folder 1268)
  - Box 18, folder 372 (Box 54, Folder 1269)
  - Box 20, folder 409 (Box 54, Folder 1270)
  - Box 22, folder 477 (Box 54, Folder 1271)
  - Box 23, folder 486 (Box 54, Folder 1272)
  - Box 23, folders 488-89 (Box 54, Folder 1273)
  - Box 26, folder 580 (Box 54, Folder 1274)
  - Box 27, folders 615-16 (Box 54, Folder 1275)
  - Box 30, folder 715 (Box 54, Folder 1276)
  - Box 30, folder 727 (Box 54, Folder 1277)
  - Box 31, folders 748-49 (Box 54, Folder 1278)
  - Box 31, folder 751 (Box 54, Folder 1279)
  - Box 34, folder 804 (Box 54, Folder 1280)
  - Box 34, folders 818-21 (Box 54, Folder 1281)
  - Box 35, folder 836 (Box 54, Folder 1282)
  - Box 35, folder 853 (Box 54, Folder 1283)
  - Box 36, folder 888 (Box 54, Folder 1284)
  - Box 37, folders 912-13 (Box 54, Folder 1285)
  - Box 38, folder 935 (Box 54, Folder 1286)
  - Box 39, folder 968 (Box 54, Folder 1287)
  - Box 41, folder 1039 (Box 54, Folder 1288)
  - Box 43, folder 1059 (Box 54, Folder 1289)
  - Box 44, folders 1082-83 (Box 54, Folder 1290)
  - Box 44, folder 1085 (Box 54, Folder 1291)
  - Box 44, folder 1089 (Box 54, Folder 1292)
  - Box 44, folder 1090 (Box 54, Folder 1293)
  - Box 45, folders 1125-26 (Box 54, Folder 1294)
  - Box 45, folder 1130 (Box 54, Folder 1295)
  - Box 45, folder 1133 (Box 54, Folder 1296)
  - Box 45, folder 1134 (Box 54, Folder 1297)
  - Box 46, folder 1158 (Box 54, Folder 1298)
  - Box 46, folder 1161 (Box 54, Folder 1299)
  - Box 46, folder 1173 (Box 54, Folder 1300)
  - Box 46, folder 1180 (Box 54, Folder 1301)
  - Box 49, folder 1232 (Box 54, Folder 1302)
  - Box 49, folder 1233 (Box 54, Folder 1303)
  - Box 49, folder 1234 (Box 54, Folder 1304)
  - Box 49, folder 1235 (Box 54, Folder 1305)
  - Box 49, folder 1236 (Box 54, Folder 1306)
  - Box 50, folder 1237 (Box 54, Folder 1307)
  - Box 50, folder 1238 (Box 54, Folder 1308)
  - Box 50, folder 1239 (Box 54, Folder 1309)
  - Box 50, folder 1240 (Box 54, Folder 1310)
  - Box 50, folder 1241 (Box 54, Folder 1311)
  - Box 50, folder 1242 (Box 54, Folder 1312)
  - Box 50, folder 1243 (Box 54, Folder 1313)
  - Box 50, folder 1245 (Box 54, Folder 1314)
  - Box 50, folder 1246 (Box 54, Folder 1315)
  - Box 50, folder 1247 (Box 54, Folder 1316)